# Yu Jin (Janet)

Summary: Driven higher education professional with broad technical skill-set and multiple years experience in telecom and financial industry. Lead designer and developer in multiple production projects. Deep domain knowledge in Java, C#, Javascript and Oracle database. Research Experience on subject of Web Graph Compression at New York University. Expertise in data structures, algorithms, object oriented design and problem solving.

#### **EDUCATION**

• New York University, Master of Science, Information System (GPA: 3.5)

01/2011 - 05/2013

Nanjing University of Science and Technology, Bachelor, Computer Science(GPA: 3.2)

09/2005 - 07/2009

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

◆ Programming Languages: Java, C#, C++, C
 ◆ Database Development: Oracle, MySQL
 Web Development: Javascript, JQuery, Flex
 Scripting Languages: Php, Python, Shell

Operating System: Unix, Linux, Windows Other: Ajax, Hibernate, Struts, Spring

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Seven Points Capital, New York, NY

Software Engineer, Intern, **01/2013 – 09/2013** 

- Lead designer and developer in a 3 member programmer team for intraday real-time equity trading system with object oriented Easy Language on Trade-Station platform and bridge api to Sterling broker system.
- Handled all modules: algorithm decision module, risk management module, order management module and stock screener.
- Experienced with various standard trading signal calculation and new trading signal design.
- Lead architect and developer of the enterprise internal web site with amazon EC2 cloud, amazon RDS database and php, javacript, implemented drag-drop mouse events and treeview menu.

## Citi Bank, New York, NY

Software Engineer, Intern, **09/2012 – 01/2013** 

- Lead architect and developer of a 4 member programmer team in Citi Enterprise Collabration Project.
- Developed an javascript object-oriented web client which support instant messaging, chat-room, voice/video conference, sync with existing IM client and communicates to a Cisco BOSH server component on Linux using Jabber open source protocols.
- Implemented contact-aware integration between other web applications (JIRA, PTS-W, TRS) and the IM client to seamlessly invoke conversations with individuals
- Use of various technologies and tools: Javascript, Jquery, HTML/HTML5, Jabber(XMPP), Ajax, Bootstrap Twitter Framework, Google Fronts API, CSS, firebug, Aptana IDE, Photoshop.
- Tested it on Windows, iOS and various browsers: Internet Explorer 7+, Firefox 6+, Chrome 10+, Safari 5.1

#### ZTE, China

Software Engineer, Dept. of International R&D, 05/2009 - 01/2011

- Largest Chinese mobile vendor. Directly developed and supported for products release in multi versions and multi countries.
- Lead Java/C# developer in Pakistan project and Singapore project. Monthly best graded software engineer of department
- Expertise in backend and frontend development on IBM server with Oracle database of Telecom Operations Support System
   Handled CRM sub-system which process customers mgmt, orders mgmt, products mgmt, fee plans mgmt and billing info
- mgmt of various products for both web portal channel and text message channel with multiple interface to external system

  Improved efficiency in this real-time online charging system which requires large scale capacity, high stability and reliability
- Improved efficiency in this real-time online charging system which requires large scale capacity, high stability and reliability
   Use of various technology: Java, C#, Javascript, Jquery, Oracle 10g/11g, Unix, Ajax, Struts, Sql procedure, MML protocol,
- Fiddler, Java Decompiler, CodeSmith, JDBC

## **PROJECTS**

## Machine Learning (Inferring causal genes in LMS(cancer) using Lasso), New York University

05/2012

• Analysis sparse causal factors and implemented least angle regression algorithm in Matlab

## Network Chat Room (Java), New York University

12/2011

- Designed and developed a GUI chat client with Swing and Awt.
- Implemented a multi-threading concurrent server which communicates with clients through sockets by TCP/IP protocol

## Web Graph Compression, New York University

08/2011

- Analysis web graph compression algorithms in various dissertations
- Analysis efficiency of Cassandra and Voldemort and learned hadoop mapreduce programming

## Extracurriculum

- ACM team member
- 3<sup>rd</sup> Place on Campus Advanced Mathematics Contest and participated in Province Math Contest as university representative
- Outstanding Graduation Dissertation: Oil pipeline leakage detection based on Fourier Transition Algorithm